<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<resources>
  <string name="app_name_medium">Bible Study App (And Bible)</string>
  <string name="app_name_long">Bible Study App, by And Bible Open Source Project</string>
  <!--Main menu-->
  <!--Passage navigation-->
  <!--Search-->
  <string name="create_index_for">To search a document we need an index. \n\nCreate an index for %s?</string>
  <!--Tasks-->
  <!--Search-->
  <!--Preferences-->
  <string name="auto_fullscreen_summary">Switch automatically to full screen when scrolling text. Tip: you can always also switch to full screen by double tapping screen.</string>
  <string name="prefs_margin_size_summary">Adjust left and right margin of the text view. You can also
        adjust the maximum width of the text.
    </string>
  <string name="full_screen_hide_buttons_pref_summary">When switching to fullscreen mode, hide window button bar that is on the bottom of the screen automatically</string>
  <!--Colors preferences-->
  <!--Window-->
  <!--Notes screen-->
  <!--Strongs-->
  <!--Module download-->
  <string name="do_not_ask_again">Yes, do not ask again</string>
  <!--Install zip file-->
  <string name="overwrite_files">Following files already exist: %s Overwrite?</string>
  <!--Daily Reading Plan-->
  <!--Document context menu-->
  <!--Verse context menu-->
  <!--Link context menu-->
  <!--Bookmarks-->
  <string name="label_unlabelled">Unlabeled</string>
  <string name="auto_assign_labels_primary">Set as the main label</string>
  <!--can be removed-->
  <!--Sort orders used for Bookmarks and MyNotes-->
  <!--Dictionary-->
  <!--General Book-->
  <!--Speak-->
  <!--plurals tags referencing the below have been moved to untranslated_strings.xml-->
  <!--Speak - Bible-->
  <!--Speak - Commentary-->
  <!--Speak - Dictionary and other-->
  <!--Speak - Common-->
  <!--Speak - Bible-->
  <string name="auto_assing_labels_help1">Here you can add, edit and remove labels. 

Selected labels: labels that apply to the current bookmark.
Recent labels: recently used labels.
Other labels: all other labels.</string>
  <!--parameter is ether setting_scope_window or setting_scope_workspace-->
  <string name="setting_scope">This setting applies only to %s.</string>
  <!--param is bookmark icon-->
  <string name="assing_labels_help2">%s indicates that this label\'s colour will be used to highlight the verse.</string>
  <!--param is auto-assign label icon-->
  <string name="assing_labels_help3">Tap %s icon to have that label assigned automatically to new bookmarks.</string>
  <!--param is heart icon-->
  <string name="assing_labels_help4">Tap %s to add the label to your favourite labels list for easy access.</string>
  <!--param is refresh icon-->
  <!--Parameter is actual icon-->
  <!--Parameter is actual icon-->
  <!--First parameter is actual icon. Second parameter is either "default values" or "workspace default values"-->
  <string name="speak_help_auto_bookmark">
        A Speak bookmark will be automatically added when Speak is paused or stopped.
        Automatically generated bookmarks are labelled with the special Speak label.
        If you start at a Speak bookmark the bookmark will be moved to the verse you
        stop or pause next time. Only Speak labels will be moved, any other labels
        will be left alone.
    </string>
  <string name="speak_help_playback_settings">
        Special playback settings (under \"Playback Settings\" on the Speak screen)
        are saved to Speak bookmarks when this setting is selected.
        When you restart speaking from a Speak bookmark, the saved playback settings
        are loaded from the bookmark.
    </string>
  <string name="speak_help_playback_settings_example">
        For example if you are listening to Genesis and Romans and
        wish to listen to Genesis spoken quickly without chapter change notifications,
        but to Romans more slowly with audible earcon sounds on chapter changes, then
        you can have different playback settings for these books,
        when these settings are saved to the corresponding bookmarks.
    </string>
  <!--List of (max 5) words that will be searched and replaced by their counterpart in divinename_replace
         if they are found in <divineName> tag in the document (i.e. LORD etc, in capital letters).

         Please note that this is not translation but you need to think about what words need to be replaced
         in your language. These will be used if "Replace divinename with Yahweh" feature is enabled
         in speak settings.-->
  <!--List of (max 5) words that we will replace those words listed in divinename_original.

         Please note that this is not translation but you need to think about what words need to be replaced
         in your language. These will be used if "Replace divinename with Yahweh" feature is enabled
         in speak settings.-->
  <string name="verse_range_mode_disabled">
        Repeat passage mode was disabled automatically because
        speaking was started outside of defined verse range.
    </string>
  <!--User Notes-->
  <!--Backup and restore-->
  <!--What items (study pads, bookmarks etc) user wants to restore from app db backup file?-->
  <string name="backup_modules_email_message_2">Attached is your %s module backup, which contains the following modules: %s</string>
  <!--About-->
  <!--Bug reporting-->
  <!--Document types-->
  <!--Languages-->
  <!--General-->
  <!--Errors-->
  <!--Notifications-->
  <!--Workspaces-->
  <string name="give_name_workspace">New workspace name</string>
  <!--Beta notice-->
  <string name="beta_notice_content_1">
        In the beta version, there are new features that are not yet properly tested,
        and thus using beta might introduce unexpected behavior, i.e. bugs.
        It is recommended that ordinary Bible readers use stable versions instead.
    </string>
  <string name="upgrade_video_message">Please see the video highlighting new features of this release (%s).</string>
  <!--History-->
  <!--Help-->
  <string name="help_nav_text">Go to the next or previous chapter by swiping left or right..
        Double-tap the document window to toggle full screen mode.
       The menu button at the top-right corner of each window 
provides easy access to manipulate and customize the window.</string>
  <string name="help_contextmenus_text">
        A long press opens a context menu in several views.
        Long press on the Bible view to open the action mode for actions affecting the current verse.
        Long press on a document item in list view of Choose Document or Download to delete document or view information.
        Long press a bookmark in bookmarks listing to add labels or delete bookmark.
        Long press links to choose if you want to open them in the current window, new window or special links window.
    </string>
  <string name="help_search_text">Search text can include special characters like *, ?, AND, OR, NOT
        (see \"Apache Lucene - Query Parser Syntax\" for more details)
    </string>
  <string name="help_workspaces_text">
Workspaces allow having multiple working environments. Workspace functions can be accessed via the Workspaces item in the options menu (top-right corner). A quick way to access workspaces is by a swipe-down gesture from the Bible reference text in the toolbar. You may also use swipe-left and swipe-right gestures over the Bible reference text in the toolbar to switch to previous or next workspace.  </string>
  <string name="help_hidden_features_text">
        Swipe down starting on the bible verse selector to show the workspace selector.
        Long press the window button to quickly minimize.
        Long press the Speak toolbar button to quickly go to speak settings.
        Long press the verse location title in toolbar to jump to document selector.
        Long press the Back button to access the History list.
    </string>
  <!--Welcome text-->
  <string name="welcome_message">Thank you for downloading %s. There are currently no Bibles installed. To continue, please install
        at least 1 Bible document by downloading from the internet, or by loading from a zip file document
        backup.
    </string>
  <!--Uncategorized-->
  <!--1. parameter is current Webview version. 2. minimum version 3. app name 4. Google Play link that takes user to WebView entry in Google Play to upgrade it.-->
  <!--parameters are actions (file a bug, send email)-->
  <!--param is "please report maintainers"-->
  <!--param is "please read what you can do"-->
  <string name="rate_message4">
The developers of this app are not responsible for maintaining documents (Bibles, commentaries, books etc).</string>
  <string name="primary_label">Main label</string>
  <string name="delete_label_confirmation">Do you want to remove the bookmark label \"%s\"? ALL associated Study Pad notes will also be removed.</string>
  <string name="bookmark_underline_style_arbitrary">Use underline style for selection bookmarks</string>
  <string name="bookmark_underline_style_whole_verse">Use underline style for whole verse bookmarks</string>
  <string name="reset_workspace_labels">Do you want to reset the label auto-assign and favorite settings for this workspace?</string>
  <string name="reset_hide_labels">Do you want to reset the hidden label settings?</string>
  <!--First param is language name, second is app name (app_name_long), third is "instruction for translators" which will be marked as a hyperlink in dialog. I hope we will never need this string, but nobody knows if some translators will drop us one day ...-->
  <!--will be added to incomplete_translation as a link-->
  <!--Android 12 requires new permission, and we need to add this string here for TTS users-->
  <!--Android 12 requires new permission, and we need to add this string here for TTS users-->
</resources>
