<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<resources>
  <!--Main menu-->
  <!--Passage navigation-->
  <!--Search-->
  <!--Tasks-->
  <!--Search-->
  <!--Preferences-->
  <string name="auto_fullscreen_summary">Switch automatically to full screen when scrolling text. Tip: you can always also switch to full screen by double tapping screen.</string>
  <string name="prefs_margin_size_summary">Adjust left and right margin of the text view. You can also
        adjust the maximum width of the text.
    </string>
  <string name="hide_window_buttons_summary">Window buttons that are displayed on the right side of the Bible views are hidden. Window navigation bar on the bottom is still displayed and you may open the window popup menu by long-clicking them.</string>
  <string name="full_screen_hide_buttons_pref_summary">When switching to fullscreen mode, hide window button bar that is on the bottom of the screen automatically</string>
  <!--Colors preferences-->
  <!--Window-->
  <!--Notes screen-->
  <!--Strongs-->
  <!--Module download-->
  <string name="one_more_back_press">Press back button again to close app</string>
  <string name="download_question_message">If you live in a persecuted country,
        you may need to be careful about downloading Christian material via the internet.
        Instead, you may want to obtain the module zip files more securely and install them
        via \"Load Documents From Zip\". Are you sure you want to proceed with downloading?
        All downloads from module repositories are encrypted (HTTPS).
    </string>
  <string name="do_not_ask_again">Yes, do not ask again</string>
  <!--Install zip file-->
  <string name="overwrite_files">Following files already exist: %s Overwrite?</string>
  <!--Daily Reading Plan-->
  <!--Document context menu-->
  <!--Verse context menu-->
  <!--Link context menu-->
  <!--Bookmarks-->
  <!--Sort orders used for Bookmarks and MyNotes-->
  <!--Dictionary-->
  <!--General Book-->
  <!--Speak-->
  <!--plurals tags referencing the below have been moved to untranslated_strings.xml-->
  <!--Speak - Bible-->
  <!--Speak - Commentary-->
  <!--Speak - Dictionary and other-->
  <!--Speak - Common-->
  <!--Speak - Bible-->
  <string name="speak_help_auto_bookmark">
        A Speak bookmark will be automatically added when Speak is paused or stopped.
        Automatically generated bookmarks are labelled with the special Speak label.
        If you start at a Speak bookmark the bookmark will be moved to the verse you
        stop or pause next time. Only Speak labels will be moved, any other labels
        will be left alone.
    </string>
  <string name="speak_help_playback_settings">
        Special playback settings (under \"Playback Settings\" on the Speak screen)
        are saved to Speak bookmarks when this setting is selected.
        When you restart speaking from a Speak bookmark, the saved playback settings
        are loaded from the bookmark.
    </string>
  <string name="speak_help_playback_settings_example">
        For example if you are listening to Genesis and Romans and
        wish to listen to Genesis spoken quickly without chapter change notifications,
        but to Romans more slowly with audible earcon sounds on chapter changes, then
        you can have different playback settings for these books,
        when these settings are saved to the corresponding bookmarks.
    </string>
  <!--List of (max 5) words that will be searched and replaced by their counterpart in divinename_replace
         if they are found in <divineName> tag in the document (i.e. LORD etc, in capital letters).

         Please note that this is not translation but you need to think about what words need to be replaced
         in your language. These will be used if "Replace divinename with Yahweh" feature is enabled
         in speak settings.-->
  <!--List of (max 5) words that we will replace those words listed in divinename_original.

         Please note that this is not translation but you need to think about what words need to be replaced
         in your language. These will be used if "Replace divinename with Yahweh" feature is enabled
         in speak settings.-->
  <string name="verse_range_mode_disabled">
        Repeat passage mode was disabled automatically because
        speaking was started outside of defined verse range.
    </string>
  <!--User Notes-->
  <!--Backup and restore-->
  <string name="backup_modules_email_message_2">Attached is your %s module backup, which contains the following modules: %s</string>
  <string name="backup_restore_message">Restore from phone storage or pick backup file manually (you can also choose from Google Drive etc.)?</string>
  <!--About-->
  <!--Bug reporting-->
  <string name="report_bug_email_message">
        --- WRITE BUG REPORT ABOVE THIS LINE ---\n
        Instructions:\n
        Tell us briefly what did you do / what happened when the issue
        took place. Example: \n
        \n
        1. Opened app\n
        2. Clicked window menu\n
         -&gt; Crash\n
        \n
        Sometimes screenshot also is beneficial in resolving issues.
        Please use this function to report as soon as you have noticed it taking place.
        You can also use this function after opening the app, after the crash has taken place.
        \n\n
        Device info: \n
        %s</string>
  <!--Document types-->
  <!--Languages-->
  <!--General-->
  <!--Errors-->
  <!--Notifications-->
  <!--Workspaces-->
  <!--Beta notice-->
  <string name="beta_notice_content_1">
        In the beta version, there are new features that are not yet properly tested,
        and thus using beta might introduce unexpected behavior, i.e. bugs.
        It is recommended that ordinary Bible readers use stable versions instead.
    </string>
  <!--History-->
  <!--Help-->
  <string name="help_nav_text">Go to the next or previous chapter by swiping the screen with your finger.
        Double-tap Bible text to toggle full screen mode.
        Split screens (called also windows) have a menu button on their top-right corner,
        which enables you to use several window-specific functions and customize window outlook and behaviour.</string>
  <string name="help_contextmenus_text">
        Long pressing opens the context menu or action mode in several views.
        Long press on the Bible view to open the action mode for actions affecting the current verse.
        Long press on a document item in list view of Choose Document or Download to delete document or view information.
        Long press a bookmark in bookmarks listing to add labels or delete bookmark.
        Long press links to choose if you want to open them in the current window, new window or special links window.
    </string>
  <string name="help_mynote_text">Notes can be added via the My Note menu item on the verse context menu.
        The list of existing notes can be accessed via the main menu.</string>
  <string name="help_bookmarks_text">Bookmarks can be added via the verse context menu.
        The Bookmark Manager is accessed via the main menu.
        The Bookmark Manager context menu allows bookmarks to be grouped using labels.
    </string>
  <string name="help_search_text">Search text can include special characters like *, ?, AND, OR, NOT
        (see \"Apache Lucene - Query Parser Syntax\" for more details)
    </string>
  <string name="help_workspaces_text">
        Workspaces allow having multiple context-dependent working environments. Workspace functions
        can be accessed via the Workspaces item in the options menu (top-right corner). Quick way to access workspaces is
        by a swipe-down gesture from the toolbar. You may also use swipe-left and swipe-right gestures over toolbar to
        switch to previous / next workspace.
    </string>
  <string name="help_hidden_features_text">
        Swipe down from the toolbar to show the workspace selector.
        Long press the window button to quickly minimize.
        Long press speak toolbar button to quickly go to speak settings.
        Long press verse location title in toolbar to jump to document selector.
        Long press the Back button to access the History list.
    </string>
  <string name="help_window_pinning_text">
        You can enable window pinning from the options menu (three dots, right top corner).
        If window pinning is enabled, you may show multiple pinned windows on Bible view,
        but only one non-pinned window. Pinned windows are displayed first, and then
        unpinned windows. You might want to open Bible documents as pinned windows, and
        commentaries and maps etc. as non-pinned windows. Then you can easily
        keep Bible documents open, and quickly switch between commentaries and
        other extra material when you study the Bible.
    </string>
  <!--Uncategorized-->
</resources>
